Nicole Dwenger

(317) 796-0703

nicole.ldwenger@yahoo.com www.nicoledwenger.com

Passionate front end developer and designer with a background in strategic communication. Experienced in formal research and audience analysis with a deep interest in developing intuitive products for users. A quick learner with expertise in various development languages and programs.

Experience

Lead Market Research Analyst | Boiler Communication | West Lafayette, IN

Aug 2020 - May 2021

- Led a team of three analysts to achieve yearly strategic goals in client communication
- Analyzed and researched audiences across 21 campaigns and ensured tactics are strategically targeting consumers

Research Assistant | Purdue Polytechnic Institute | West Lafayette, IN

Nov 2019 - May 2021

- Reduced student effort by researching and transforming 21 physical worksheets into a user-friendly digital format
- Developed and maintained a website with Gatsby.js for student and professor use in a data visualization course

Social Center of Expertise Intern | General Motors | Detroit, MI

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

- Benchmarked and researched social care strategies across the automotive industry and other markets
- Analyzed customer sentiments through customer satisfaction scores to determine common trends for improvement

Front End Developer | CDW | Vernon Hills, IL

Nov 2019 - May 2020

- Developed atomic components in an agile environment to be integrated into Adobe Experience Manager
- Increased code coverage by 60% on front end development repositories utilizing Mocha and Chai
- Implemented changes to repositories leveraging Git and Gulp commands for ease of documentation

Front End Developer Intern | CDW | Vernon Hills, IL

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

- Wrote standards-compliant code while testing and debugging for multiple browsers
- Collaborated with internal development and design teams to ensure effective user flow of an internal engineers' blog while leading prototype production with 16 interns
- Designed a working prototype in Adobe Experience Manager to present a proof of concept to upper management

Web Team Intern | Purdue Agricultural Communications | West Lafayette, IN

Aug 2019 - May 2020

- Created wireframes and demonstrated user flows to satisfy client requirements while maintaining 120+ sites
- Designed creative mockups and met with clients to propose design direction, usability, and coding requirements
- Researched keywords and met with content writers to prioritize search engine optimization across all sites

Summer Intern | Siemens Energy, Inc. | Indianapolis, IN

May 2018 - Aug 2018

- Maintained critical schedule for data migration project operating Siemens TeamCenter and Excel
- Developed presentation template adhering to Siemens business & color graphics requirements

Education

Purdue University | West Lafayette, IN

May 2021

- B.S. in Computer Graphics Technology, cum laude
- B.A. in Communication
- Overall GPA: 3.87 / 4.00
- Director of Internal Communication | Purdue Public Relations Student Society of America

Skills and Expertise

- Coding exposure: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, SASS, Bootstrap, React, Gatsby, PHP, SQL, C#, C++, ASP.Net
- Software: Adobe Creative Cloud, Microsoft Office, WordPress, SharePoint, Adobe Experience Manager, GitHub, Visual Studio, Figma, Miro, Chrome Developer Tools, Maya
- Experience in responsive web design, wireframing, prototyping, accessible web design, version control
- Excellent organizational skills, creative thinker, personable, and active listener
- Great at team collaboration, drives engagement, sets goals, and keeps team members on track

Honors and Awards

Persistent Pursuit: Lamb School Co-curricular Engagement | April 2021 Purdue OUR Scholars | Aug 2020 - May 2021 2021-2022 Mortar Board Cover Contest Winner | Nov 2020 Purdue Polytechnic Institute Undergraduate Conference Winner | May 2020